Gerhard Alden Gesell Papers
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
- Case File, 1956-1991 (Box 44-69)
  - Special Case File, 1969-1991 (Box 49-69)
    - United States v. North
      - Correspondence
        - General
          - Mar.-May 1989, (8 folders) (Box 54)
          - June 1989-Oct. 1991, undated, (10 folders) (Box 55)
      - Classified Information Procedures Act, draft opinions (not issued), 1988-1989
      - Diary, 1988-1991 (Box 56)
      - Dockets
        - Chambers, 1988-1991
        - General, 1988-1991
      - Exhibit list, 1989
      - Indictment, 1988
      - Jury
        - Notes, 1989
        - Selection, 1988-1989, undated (Box 57)
      - Orders, 1988-1991, (5 folders)
      - Press
        - Editorials, 1988-1991
        - General, 1988-1989
        - Political cartoons, 1988-1991 (Box 58)
      - Stipulation, undated
      - Transcripts
        - 1988
          - 24 Mar.-6 May, (6 folders)
          - 26 May-21 Nov., (3 folders) (Box 59)
        - 1989
          - 14-23 Feb., (3 folders)
          - 24 Feb.-6 Mar., (7 folders) (Box 60)
          - 6-13 Mar., (5 folders) (Box 61)
          - 14-22 Mar., (6 folders) (Box 62)
          - 22-30 Mar., (6 folders) (Box 63)
          - 31 Mar.-10 Apr., (8 folders) (Box 64)
          - 11-19 Apr., (6 folders) (Box 65)
          - 20 Apr.-28 June, (2 folders) (Box 66)
        - 1991, (3 folders)
      - Verdict form, 1989
    - United States v. Perholtz, 1988, undated See also Container 77, same heading
    - United States v. Vuitch
      - Correspondence, 1969-1970
      - General, 1969-1971, undated, (2 folders) (Box 67)
    - United States v. Washington Post Co. (Pentagon Papers case)
      - General, 1971-1981, undated, (4 folders)
      - Transcripts, 1971, undated
    - Watergate cases
      - Nader v. Bork, undated
      - Senate Select Comm. on Presidential Campaign Activities v. Nixon, 1973-1974, undated, (5 folders) (Box 68)
      - United States v. Chapin, 1973-1975, undated, (4 folders)
      - United States v. Ehrlichman (Box 69)
        - Ehrlichman, John D., notes, redacted copies, 1971
        - General, 1971-1974, undated, (4 folders)
        - Indictment, undated
        - Jury
          - Charge to, 1974
          - Selection procedure and statistics, 1974
        - Marshal's office, 1975
        - Nixon, Richard M., 1974, 1982, 1991
        - Orders, 1974
        - Press, 1974-1975, undated
        - Sentencing transcript, 1974
- Bench Books, 1968-1993 (Box 70-77)
  Bound volumes containing Gesell's notes about the cases that came before his court.
  Arrangement is chronological, except for three volumes that are alphabetical by topic or case title.
  - Chronological (Box 70)
    - 2 Jan. 1968-5 May 1970, (4 folders)
    - 5 May 1970-20 Sept. 1974, (4 folders) (Box 71)
    - 24 Sept. 1974-18 Dec. 1978, (4 folders) (Box 72)
    - 2 Jan. 1979-1 Jan. 1983, (4 folders) (Box 73)
    - 1 Feb. 1983-19 Sept. 1986, (4 folders) (Box 74)
    - 22 Sept. 1986-6 Nov. 1991, (4 folders) (Box 75)
    - 12 Nov. 1991-21 Jan. 1993, (2 folders) (Box 76)
  - Other
    - Riot cases, 1968-1969 See also Container 48, see heading
    - United States v. Ehrlichman, 1974 For additional material see Container 69, same heading
    - United States v. Perholtz, 1985-1986 See also Container 66, same heading (Box 77)
- Dockets, 1959-1992 (Box 77-89)
  Docket sheets for civil and criminal cases.
  Arrangement is alphabetical by type of case, then chronological by year, and therein numerical by docket number.
  - Civil (Box 77)
    - 1962-1970, (5 folders)
    - 1970-1973, (8 folders) (Box 78)
    - 1974-1976, (8 folders) (Box 79)
    - 1977-1978, (6 folders) (Box 80)
    - 1979
      - Nos. 79-7 to 79-1252
      - Nos. 79-1265 to 79-3495, (2 folders) (Box 81)
    - 1980-1981, (5 folders)
    - 1982-1983, (7 folders) (Box 82)
    - 1984, (4 folders) (Box 83)
    - 1985
      - Nos. 85-6 to 85-3123, (3 folders)
      - Nos. 85-3153 to 85-4100 (Box 84)
    - 1986, (4 folders)
    - 1987
      - Nos. 87-4 to 87-1719, (2 folders)
      - Nos. 87-1748 to 87-3551, (2 folders) (Box 85)
    - 1988, (4 folders)
    - 1989
      - Nos. 89-5 to 89-697
      - Nos. 89-754 to 89-3449, (4 folders) (Box 86)
    - 1990
      - Nos. 90-2 to 90-2985, (3 folders)
      - Nos. 90-503 to 90-3144, (4 folders) (Box 87)
  - Criminal
    - Index, undated (only cases for Oct. 1968-July 1978)
    - 1959-1969, (3 folders)
    - 1970-1977, (7 folders) (Box 88)
    - 1978-1992, (8 folders) (Box 89)
- Sentencing File, 1968-1992 (Box 90-157)
  Correspondence, memoranda, presentence reports, orders, card files, and related sentencing information for Gesell's criminal cases.
  Arrangement is alphabetical by type of material or topic and therein alphabetical by name of defendant, except the presentencing file which is arranged chronologically and therein alphabetically by name of defendant.
  - Defendants sentence file, 1968-1992 (card files) (Box OV 90)
    - A-E
    - F-K (Box OV 91)
    - L-R (Box OV 92)
    - S-Z (Box OV 93)
  - Defendants whose cases were dismissed or were found not guilty, 1968-1992 (Box OV 94)
  - Presentencing file (Box 95)
    - 1968-1979
      - Abr-Bai, (6 folders)
      - Bak-Big See also Classified, (6 folders) (Box 96)
      - Bla-Bro, (6 folders) (Box 97)
      - Bro-Bry, (7 folders) (Box 98)
      - Buc-Cha, (8 folders) (Box 99)
      - Cha-Col, (6 folders) (Box 100)
      - Col, (8 folders) (Box 101)
      - Col-Dav, (6 folders) (Box 102)
      - Daw-Ehr, (7 folders) (Box 103)
      - Ela-Fog, (7 folders) (Box 104)
      - For-Gat, (7 folders) (Box 105)
      - Gau-Guy, (6 folders) (Box 106)
      - Hai-Haz, (6 folders) (Box 107)
      - Hea-Jac, (8 folders) (Box 108)
      - Jac-Joh, (7 folders) (Box 109)
      - Jon-Kri, (6 folders) (Box 110)
      - Kro-Law, (7 folders) (Box 111)
      - Law-Low, (7 folders) (Box 112)
      - Luc-Mat, (7 folders) (Box 113)
      - Mat-Mer See also Classified, (7 folders) (Box 114)
      - Mer-Moo, (7 folders) (Box 115)
      - Moo-Mur, (8 folders) (Box 116)
      - Mur-Pat, (8 folders) (Box 117)
      - Pat-Pri, (7 folders) (Box 118)
      - Pro-Rob, (8 folders) (Box 119)
      - Ros-Shi, (7 folders) (Box 120)
      - Sho-Spr, (7 folders) (Box 121)
      - Sta-Tay, (6 folders) (Box 122)
      - Tho-Vir, (7 folders) (Box 123)
      - Wad-Whi, (6 folders) (Box 124)
      - Whi-Wil, (8 folders) (Box 125)
      - Wil-Zer, (8 folders) (Box 126)
      - Zer (Box 127)
    - 1980-1989
      - Adg-Bat, (7 folders)
      - Bel-Bro, (5 folders) (Box 128)
      - Bro-Byr, (4 folders) (Box 129)
      - Cag-Col, (8 folders) (Box 130)
      - Col, (5 folders) (Box 131)
      - Col-Dan, (8 folders) (Box 132)
      - Dat-Dil, (8 folders) (Box 133)
      - Doe-Duv, (7 folders) (Box 134)
      - Eat-Fun, (7 folders) (Box 135)
      - Gai-Guz, (7 folders) (Box 136)
      - Had, (7 folders) (Box 137)
      - Har-How, (7 folders) (Box 138)
      - How-Jef, (7 folders) (Box 139)
      - Jef-Joh, (8 folders) (Box 140)
      - Jon-Lea, (7 folders) (Box 141)
      - Lea-Mat, (8 folders) (Box 142)
      - Mcf-Mul, (7 folders) (Box 143)
      - Mul-Owe, (9 folders) (Box 144)
      - Pab-Per, (7 folders) (Box 145)
      - Per-Rob, (7 folders) (Box 146)
      - Rod-Rut, (7 folders) (Box 147)
      - Rut-Ser, (7 folders) (Box 148)
      - Sho-Tri, (8 folders) (Box 149)
      - Ven-Wat, (7 folders) (Box 150)
      - Wea-Zio, (6 folders) (Box 151)
    - 1990-1992 (Box 152)
      - Ale-Col, (9 folders)
      - Con-Fos, (11 folders) (Box 153)
      - Ful-Kun, (11 folders) (Box 154)
      - Lee-Ort, (10 folders) (Box 155)
      - Pai-Ste, (10 folders) (Box 156)
      - Sut-You, (9 folders) (Box 157)
- Office File, 1965-1993 (Box 158-170)
  Correspondence, memoranda, reports, background information, agendas and minutes of meetings, notes, press files, and printed matter.
  - Advisory Committee to the Chief Justice Regarding Court Administrators, 1969-1970, undated (Box 158)
  - District of Columbia Circuit History Committee, 1969, 1990-1992, undated, (2 folders)
  - District of Columbia Commission on Judicial Tenure and Disabilities, 1976-1980, undated, (3 folders)
  - Dispositions in civil and criminal cases
    - 1971-1988
    - 1989-1993 (Box 159)
  - Edward J. Devitt Distinguished Service to Justice Award, 1990, (2 folders)
  - Federal court guidelines questionnaire, 1993
  - Federal-District of Columbia Courts Committee, 1971-1976
  - Federal Judicial Center
    - Ad Hoc Committee on Reading Materials, 1984-1985, undated
    - Bench Comment draft, 1983
    - Board of directors, 1970-1972, (2 folders)
    - Case management videotape, 1985-1986
  - Individual calendar system
    - 1968-1969, (2 folders)
    - 1970-1990, undated (Box 160)
  - Judicial Conference
    - District of Columbia Circuit
      - Committee on Arrangements for the 1977 Judicial Conference, 1976-1977
      - Court of Appeals/District Court Liaison Committee, 1973-1974
      - Joint Committee on Pro Se Appellate Mandamus Petitioners, 1990-1991
      - Program Committee, 1968-1969, (3 folders)
    - United States
      - Advisory Committee on Criminal Rules
        - 1969-1970, (3 folders)
        - 1971-1974 (Box 161)
      - Committee on Operation of the Jury System
        - General, 1968-1970, (2 folders)
        - Subcommittee on the "Fair Press-Free Trial" Issue
          - Ad Hoc Committee, 1978-1980, undated, (3 folders)
          - General
            - 1965-1969, (2 folders)
            - 1970-1981, undated, (5 folders) (Box 162)
      - District of Columbia Circuit Conference Committee on New Rules of Evidence, 1969-1970, undated
  - Judicial Council of the District of Columbia Circuit Conference, Committee on Attorneys' Fees, 1983
  - Jury instructions
    - 1968-1979
    - 1980-1989, undated, (4 folders) (Box 163)
  - Press
    - General
      - 1969-1985, (5 folders)
      - 1986-1993, undated, (2 folders) (Box 164)
    - Political cartoons, 1970-1974, undated
  - Temporary Emergency Court of Appeals, 1983
  - United States Court of Appeals for the District of Columbia
    - Circuit
      - Assignments, 1986, undated
      - Designations, 1976-1989
      - Judgments, 1988-1993, (3 folders)
      - Sittings
        - 1976-1977, (3 folders)
        - 1978-1986, (9 folders) (Box 165)
        - 1987-1990, (2 folders) (Box 166)
  - United States District Court for the District of Columbia
    - Appointment to
      - Correspondence, 1967-1968, (3 folders)
      - General, 1967-1968, undated
    - Attorney admissions, 1986-1992
    - Auditor, 1968-1970
    - Committees
      - Advisory Committee on Local Rules
        - 1974-1977, (2 folders)
        - 1978-1981, (2 folders) (Box 167)
      - Committee on Grievances
        - Federal Rules of Disciplinary Enforcement, 1977-1980
        - General, 1977-1989, (4 folders)
        - McGean, Donald C., 1982-1984 (Box 168)
      - Committee on Non-appropriated Funds, 1981-1984
      - Committee to Draw Up Plan for Expediting Criminal Cases, 1972-1974
      - Committee to Investigate Discrimination in Assignment of Cases to Judges, 1969
      - Committee to Recommend Procedure to Be Followed After Verdict of Not Guilty By Reason of Insanity
        - 1968, undated
      - Committee to Review Standards for Admission to the Bar of the Court, 1986-1988, (4 folders)
      - Committee to Review Local Rules, 1971-1973
      - Disbarment Committee, 1972-1973
      - Miscellaneous, 1968-1970 (Box 169)
    - Indigent Civil Litigation Panel
      - 1982-1991, (7 folders)
      - 1992, undated, (3 folders) (Box 170)
    - Rule 711 Counseling Panel, 1989-1992
  - Watergate, 1990-1992
- Miscellany, 1945-1993 (Box 170-171)
  Chiefly speeches and writings by Gesell and his clerks. Also included are slides, photographs, political cartoons, and tributes to Gesell after his death.
  Arrangement is alphabetical by topic or type of material.
  - Photograph, undated
  - Political cartoons, 1945, undated
  - Speeches
    - 1975, (2 folders)
    - 1976-1991, (6 folders) (Box 171)
  - Tributes to Gesell given at his memorial service and obituaries, 1993
  - Writings
    - By Gesell
      - General, 1981, 1989
      - Notebook of memoranda and memoir, "My Jealous Mistress," 1990, undated
    - Bylaw clerks, 1983-1984
- 2018 Addition, 1913-2003 (Box 172)
  Correspondence, memoranda, case files, family papers, financial papers and ledgers, farm ledgers, reports, maps, speeches and speech material, writings, college class papers, memorials and tributes, certificates, newspaper clippings, printed matter, and other material.
  Arranged alphabetically by name or organization, topic, or type of material.
  - Awards and honors, 1954-1992 See also Oversize (Box 172)
  - Bar admissions and applications, 1941-1943 See also Oversize (Box 172)
  - Biographical file, 1963-1993, undated See also Oversize, (2 folders) (Box 172)
  - Birthday, seventieth, 1980, (2 folders) (Box 172)
  - Calendar, 1993 (Box 172)
  - Committee on the Administration of Justice, 1966-1967, (3 folders) (Box 172)
  - Correspondence (Box 172)
    - 1940-1953, (3 folders) (Box 172)
    - 1954-1961, (12 folders) (Box 173)
    - 1962-1965, (9 folders) (Box 174)
    - 1966 (Box 174)
      - Jan.-Mar. (Box 174)
      - May-Dec., (2 folders) (Box 175)
    - 1967-1974, (12 folders) (Box 175)
    - 1975-1980, (17 folders) (Box 176)
    - 1981-1993, undated, (13 folders) (Box 177)
  - Covington & Burling (Box 177)
    - Correspondence, 1957-1967, (3 folders) (Box 177)
    - Notebooks about cases (Box 178)
      - Vol. 1, A-F, 1950-1967, (3 folders) (Box 178)
      - Vol. 2, G-P, 1952-1967, (3 folders) (Box 178)
      - Vol. 3, P-W, 1959-1967, (3 folders) (Box 178)
  - Death (Box 179)
    - Condolence letters (Box 179)
      - 1993 (Box 179)
        - Feb.-Mar., (11 folders) (Box 179)
        - Apr.-Dec. (Box 180)
      - 1994 (Box 180)
    - General, 1992-1993 (Box 180)
    - Guest books from memorial service and home gathering, 1993 (Box 180)
    - Press, 1993 (Box 180)
  - Expediting Act, 1966 (Box 180)
  - Family papers, 1913-1971, 1990-1998, undated, (2 folders) (Box 180)
  - Farm, Loudon County, Va. (Box 180)
    - Beaverdam Creek, impoundment project 1966-1969 (Box 180)
    - Bills and receipts, selected sample by family, 1986-1994, (2 folders) (Box 180)
    - Card file of equipment and livestock purchases, 1967-1993 (Box 181)
    - Construction of new house on parcel no. 4, 1969 (Box 181)
    - Deed of three acres to Mount Hope Baptist Church, Waxpool, Va., 1970 (Box 181)
    - General, 1976-1998, (5 folders) (Box 181)
    - Income, 1975-1985, 1991, (3 folders) (Box 182)
    - Ledger books (Box 182)
      - 1953-1965, (10 folders) (Box 182)
      - 1966-1993, (11 folders) (Box 183)
    - Loans, 1951-1969 (Box 183)
    - Maps, undated (Box 183)
    - Purchase and description of parcels (Box 184)
      - No. 1 (main farm), 1953-1972 (Box 184)
      - No. 2 (Ebel), 1954-1972 (Box 184)
      - No. 3 (Holden), 1957-1963 (Box 184)
      - No. 4 (Wortman), 1953-1963 (Box 184)
      - No. 5 (Greenway), 1962-1968, (2 folders) (Box 184)
      - No. 6 (Adrian), 1961-1963 (Box 184)
    - Reservoir issues, 1970, 1978-1983 (Box 184)
    - Road work, Routes 621 and 625, 1975-1983 (Box 184)
    - Sale of Greenway Farm, 1973-1994, (2 folders) (Box 184)
    - Silos, 1967 (Box 184)
    - Taxation based on land assessment, 1972-1993, (1 folder) (Box 184, Box 185)
    - Telephone and electric wires, 1970-1971 (Box 185)
    - Virginia Electric and Power Co., eminent domain, 1963-1965, (2 folders) (Box 185)
  - Financial ledgers (Box 185)
    - General (Box 185)
      - 1931-1948, (3 folders) (Box 185)
      - 1949-1973, (4 folders) (Box 186)
      - 1966-1992, (5 folders) (Box 187)
      - 1993-2009, (2 folders) (Box 188)
    - Income, 1949-1963 (Box 188)
  - Financial papers, 1957-1994, (2 folders) (Box 188)
  - Humphrey, Hubert H., 1964-1968 (Box 188)
  - Joint Committee on the Investigation of the Pearl Harbor Attack (Box 188)
    - Congressional committee prints, 1946 (Box 188)
    - Scrapbook, 1944-1946 (Box 189)
  - Library of Congress, 1976, 1992-1993 (Box 189)
  - Maine, 1971-1976, 1982, undated (Box 189)
  - Memorials and tributes, 1973-1992 (Box 189)
  - Miscellany, 1928-1930, 1954, 1967-1968, 1987-1992, undated (Box 189)
  - Moot court, 1976-1979 (Box 189)
  - Oral history, 1990-1992, 2000, 2011, (1 folder) (Box 189, Box 190)
  - Phillips Academy, Andover, Mass., 1973 (Box 190)
  - Political file (Box 190)
    - Citizens Committee for Good Government, circa 1964 (Box 190)
    - Democratic Central Committee of the District of Columbia, 1951-1955 (Box 190)
    - Inaugural Committee of 1965, 1965-1967, (2 folders) (Box 190)
    - Presidential campaigns (Box 190)
      - 1956, (2 folders) (Box 190)
      - 1960, (2 folders) (Box 190)
      - 1964, (2 folders) (Box 191)
      - 1984 (Box 191)
  - President's Committee on Equal Opportunity in the Armed Services, 1963-1964, 1974, (3 folders) (Box 191)
  - Recommendations (Box 191)
    - 1941-1959, (5 folders) (Box 191)
    - 1960-1975, (4 folders) (Box 192)
  - Securities and Exchange Commission (Box 192)
    - 1936-1938, (8 folders) (Box 192)
    - 1939-1940, (11 folders) (Box 193)
    - 1941, 1944, 1990, (3 folders) (Box 194)
  - Speech material, 1989-1990 (Box 194)
  - Speeches by Gesell, 1975-1976, 1989-1990, (4 folders) (Box 194)
  - United States District Court for the District of Columbia (Box 194)
    - Case management, 1983 (Box 194)
    - Closed cases, 1985-1992 (Box 194)
    - Congratulatory correspondence on appointment as judge, 1968 (Box 194)
    - Court management, 1970-1972, 1990 (Box 194)
    - Judges, undated (Box 195)
    - Law clerks, 1993, undated (Box 195)
    - List of Gesell's court of appeals sittings, 1990 (Box 195)
    - List of Gesell's published opinions, 1991 (Box 195)
    - Marriage services and license certificates, 1972-1991 (Box 195)
    - Miscellany, 1974-1988, undated (Box 195)
    - Press (Box 195)
      - 1970-1993, undated, (3 folders) (Box 195)
    - United States v. Ehrlichman, 1974 (Box 195)
    - United States v. North (Box 195)
      - General, 1990-1993 (Box 195)
      - Press (Box 195)
        - Articles (Box 195)
          - 1988, (3 folders) (Box 195)
          - 1989 (Box 195)
            - Jan. (Box 195)
            - Feb.-Nov., (6 folders) (Box 196)
          - 1990-1991, undated, (2 folders) (Box 196)
        - Cartoons, 1989-1991 (Box 196)
        - Editorials, 1988-1991 (Box 196)
      - Trial transcript summary, 1989 (Box 196)
      - United States Court of Appeals for the District of Columbia Circuit and the Supreme Court, 1990-1991, (2 folders) (Box 196)
    - United States v. Poindexter, undated (Box 197)
    - United States v. Seegers, 1979 (Box 197)
    - United States v. Smith, 1976 (Box 197)
    - United States v. Washington Post Co., in camera proceedings, 1971 (Box 197)
  - United States savings bonds, 1940-1949 (Box 197)
  - Vietnam, 1961-1965, (2 folders) (Box 197)
  - White House Conference to "Fulfill These Rights," Washington, D.C., 1965 (Box 197)
  - Writings by Gesell (Box 197)
    - 1940-1981, (2 folders) (Box 197)
    - 1984, (2 folders); (1 folder) (Box 197, Box 198)
    - 1990 (Box 198)
  - Writings by others, 1980, 1994, 2003 (Box 198)
  - Yale Law School, New Haven, Conn. (Box 198)
    - Citation of merit, 1967 (Box 198)
    - General, 1933-1935, 1966, 1979, 1993, 2004, undated, (2 folders) (Box 198)
  - Yale University, New Haven, Conn., 1932, 1984-1992, (3 folders) (Box 198)
- Classified, 1968-1979 (Box CL 1)
  Government classified documents containing sensitive security information.
  Presentencing material organized and described according to the series, boxes, and folders from which the items were removed.
  - Sentencing file (Box CL 1)
    - Presentencing file
      - 1968-1979
        - Bak-Bark (Container 96)
        - Mart-Mas (Container 113)
- Oversize, 1941-1990 (Box OV 1)
  Oversize certificates relating to Gesell's professional career.
  Arranged and described according to the series, containers, and folders from which the items were removed.
  - 2018 Addition (Box OV 1)
    - Certificate for the Edward J. Devitt Distinguished Service to Justice Award, 1990 (Container 172, Awards and honors) (Box OV 1)
    - Certificate to the bar of the Supreme Court, 1941 (Container 172, Bar admissions and applications) (Box OV 1)
    - Certificate nominating Gesell as judge of the United States District Court for the District of Columbia, 1967 (folder 2 of 2) (Container 172, Biographical file) (Box OV 1)
Appendix: Legal Abbreviations
Administrat [ive, ion] Admin.
Administrat [or, rix] Adm'[r,x]
Agriculture Agric.
America [n] Am.
Associate Assoc.
Association Ass'n
Atlantic Atl.
Authority Auth.
Automobile Auto.
Avenue Ave.
Board Bd.
Brotherhood Bhd.
Brothers Bros.
Building Bldg.
Central Cent.
Chemical Chem.
Commission Comm'n
Commissioner Comm'r
Committee Comm.
Company Co.
Consolidated Consol.
Construction Constr.
Cooperative Coop.
Corporation Corp.
Department Dep't
Development Dev.
Distribut [or, ing] Distrib.
District Dist.
Division Div.
East [ern] E.
Education [al] Educ.
Electric [al, ity] Elec.
Electronic Elec.
Engineer Eng'r
Engineering Eng'g
Enterprise Enter.
Environment Env't
Environmental Envtl.
Equipment Equip.
Exchange Exch.
Execut [or, rix] Ex'[r,x]
Federal Fed.
Federation Fed'n
Financ [e, ial, ing] Fin.
Foundation Found.
General Gen.
Government Gov't
Guaranty Guar.
Hospital Hosp.
Housing Hous.
Incorporate Inc.
Indemnity Indem.
Independent Indep.
Industr [y, ies, ial] Indus.
Institut [e, ion] Inst.
Insurance Ins.
International Int'l
Investment Inv.
Liability Liab.
Limited Ltd.
Litigation Litig.
Machine [ry] Mach.
Manufacturer Mfr.
Manufacturing Mfg.
Market Mkt.
Marketing Mktg.
Metropolitan Metro.
Municipal Mun.
Mutual Mut.
National Nat'l
North [ern] N.
Organiz [ation, ing] Org.
Pacific Pac.
Product [ion] Prod.
Public Pub.
Railroad R.R.
Railway Ry.
Refining Ref.
Road Rd.
Savings Sav.
Securit [y, ies] Sec.
Service Serv.
Society Soc'y
South [ern] S.
Steamship [s] S.S.
Street St.
Surety Sur.
System [s] Sys.
Tele [phone, graph] Tel.
Transport [ation] Transp.
University Univ.
Utility Util.
West [ern] W.